Esta lição 27 de Pimsleur Inglês 1. Dois conhecidos
estão discutindo seus planos. Você vai ouvir a mulher dizer,
"Tell me," o que quer dizer, "diga-me." Listen to this
conversation. Hello, how are you?
Fine, thanks. And you? I'm fine too. Tell me,
when are you going to Washington? Tomorrow night. And what
are you going to do today? Today I'm going to work. And you?
I'm going to see some friends. Listen again.
Hello, how are you? Fine, thanks. And you?
I'm fine too. Tell me, when are you going to Washington?
Tomorrow night. And what are you going to do today? Today I'm
going to work. And you? I'm going to see some friends.
Tell me in English. Hola.
Hello. Ask me how I am.
How are you?
Answer that you're fine.
I'm fine. I'm fine,
thanks.
Ask me if the stores are open.
Are the stores open?
Answer that they're closed.
They're closed.
No, they're closed.
Ask why.
Why? Answer, because it's late.
Because it's late.
Ask me if I'm going to work.
Are you going to work?
Say that you don't think so.
I don't think so.
Try to say, eu não acho que eu vou trabalhar.
I don't think I'm going to work.
I don't think. I don't
think I'm going to work.
Say that you're going to New York.
I'm going to New York.
Say talvez.
Maybe. Maybe.
Este é o nome de outra
cidade americana. Boston. Listen and repeat.
Boston. Boston. Boston.
Say that you're going to Boston.
I'm going to Boston.
Now say that you think you're going to Boston.
I think I'm going to Boston.
Ask him what he's going to do there. Ask him what he's
going to do there.
What are you going to do there?
Say that you're going to see some friends.
I'm going to see some friends.
Alguns amigos.
A few friends.
Say that you have a few friends there.
I have a few friends there.
Eu vou ver meus amigos.
I'm going to see my friends.
My friends.
Eu vou trabalhar.
And I'm going to work.
Talvez. Maybe.
How do you say in English? Oitenta.
Eighty. Eighty.
Now try to say noventa.
Ninety. Ninety.
Noventa e cinco.
Ninety-five.
95.
99.
89. 89.
89.
Imagine que você quer comprar algo. Pergunte-me quanto custa.
How much is it?
Answer: alguns dólares.
A few dollars.
Now say,
"Não espere, custa noventa dólares." No
wait, it's ninety dollars.
Aqui estão cem dólares. Cem.
Listen and repeat. 100.
Hundred. Drid.
Hun.
Hundred.
100. Try to say same dollars.
$100.
One hundred dollars.
Aqui estão cem dólares.
Here's one hundred dollars.
Try to say cento e cinquenta dólares e
se subentende.
One hundred fifty dollars.
Now say, cento e oitenta.
One hundred eighty.
Cento e noventa.
190. Isso é demais.
That's too much.
Cento e setenta.
One hundred seventy.
Cento e sessenta e cinco.
165. Cento e quarenta e sete.
One hundred forty-seven.
Pergunte quanto custa.
How much is it?
Say, $100.
$100. Say, isso não
é demais.
That's not too much.
Ask, por que não?
Why not?
Porque eu tenho dinheiro suficiente.
Because I have enough money.
Ask me how much I want. Ask me how much I want.
How much do you want?
Eu não quero nada. Listen and repeat.
I don't want anything.
Anything.
Thing. Thing. Any.
Anything. I don't want anything.
Say again. Eu não quero nada.
I don't want anything.
Now try to say. Eu não tenho nada.
I don't have anything.
Ask: O que você tem?
What do you have?
Answer: Eu não tenho nada.
I don't have anything.
And I don't want
anything.
Listen and repeat. I'm leaving.
Leaving.
I'm, I'm leaving.
Say that you're leaving.
I'm leaving.
How do you say? Eu não vou embora.
I'm not leaving.
Try to say, "Eu vou embora amanhã." I'm
leaving tomorrow.
I'm leaving tomorrow.
Nós vamos embora. Listen and repeat. We're leaving.
We're We are.
We're.
We're leaving.
We're é a contração de we are.
Agora diga: nós vamos embora amanhã.
We're leaving tomorrow.
We're. Nós vamos embora
juntos. Listen and repeat.
We are leaving together.
Together.
Gather. Gather. Together.
Say juntos.
Together.
Together. Say, nós vamos embora juntos.
We are leaving together.
Try to say, nós vamos.
We are going. Going.
We're going. Try to say. Nós vamos juntos para Boston.
Note que juntos se coloca geralmente no final da frase.
We're going to Boston together.
Together. We're going
to Boston together.
Minha esposa e eu.
My wife and I.
Minha esposa e eu vamos para Boston.
My wife and I are going to Boston.
Juntos. Together. Minha esposa quer
ver alguns amigos.
My wife wants to see a few friends.
E eu vou trabalhar.
And I'm going to work.
Say, "Eu não vou embora." I'm
not leaving.
I'm not leaving.
Ask, "Por que não?" Why
not? Why not?
Porque, because, porque eu
não tenho dinheiro.
Because I don't have any money.
Any money. Eu não
tenho. I don't
have any. I don't have
any.
C. Eu tenho dinheiro suficiente.
I have enough money.
Eu tenho noventa dólares.
I have ninety dollars.
Ou cem dólares.
Or one hundred dollars.
Nós vamos embora amanhã.
We're leaving tomorrow.
Nós vamos para Boston.
We're going to Boston.
Juntos. Together.
Depois. Then. Nós vamos
para Washington,
D.C. We're going to Washington, D.C.
Talvez. Maybe. Nós gostaríamos de ver Washington.
We'd like to see Washington.
E nós gostaríamos de ver nossa amiga Mary.
And we'd like to see our friend Mary.
Ella mora em Washington.
She lives in Washington.
She lives.
E ela trabalha lá.
And she works there.
She works.
Ela não tem carro. Listen and repeat. She doesn't have
a car. Doesn't,
doesn't, doesn't have.
She doesn't have.
She doesn't have a car.
Doesn't é a palavra negativa que se usa para falar de outra pessoa.
É uma contração de does not.
Diga outra vez: ela não tem carro.
Literalmente, ela não tem um carro.
She doesn't have a car.
Ela mora em Washington.
She lives in Washington.
Sem mudar a ordem das palavras, pergunte: E ela não tem carro?
And she doesn't have a car?
Por que não? Why not?
Why not? Try to
say: Ela não precisa de um carro.
She doesn't need a car.
Need. Doesn't need.
Diga as frases juntas. Ela precisa de. Ela não precisa
She needs. She doesn't need.
Now say again. Ela não tem carro.
She doesn't have a car.
Pergunte-lhe se ele tem dinheiro suficiente.
Do you have enough money?
Say, sim, eu acho que sim.
Yes, I think so.
Try to say, eu tenho duzentos dólares.
I have two hundred dollars.
Two hundred. Now try
to say, nós não precisamos de nada.
We don't need anything.
We don't. We don't
need. We don't need anything.
Say, eu não acho.
I don't think. Try to
say. Eu não acho que nós precisamos de nada.
I don't think we need anything.
And our friend.
Nossa amiga não precisa de nada.
Our friend doesn't need anything.
Nós vamos embora.
We're leaving.
Amanhã à noite.
Tomorrow night.
Ask if the department stores are open now.
Are the department stores open now? Say.
Nós não precisamos de nada.
We don't need anything.
Mas nós queremos comprar algo.
But we want to buy something.
Para nossa amiga Mary.
For our friend Mary.
Say that it's too late.
It's too late.
Too late. Say that the
department stores are closed now.
The department stores are closed now.
Say that they're open tomorrow.
They're open tomorrow.
Say, nós vamos embora amanhã.
We're leaving tomorrow.
Juntos. Together. Sei,
Boston é cara.
Boston is expensive.
Mas Washington é mais cara.
But Washington is more expensive.
Nesta lição de inglês um se incluem exercícios de leitura.